# Vitaly Bolychev

+7 921 320 2445 vitaly.bolychev@gmail.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### PROFILE INFO

I build complex backend using cutting-edge technologies. I have 8-year experience working on financial, social, and government projects for hundreds of thousands customers. I successfully apply microservices approach. I like to go into the core of architecture design and tooling.

#### **SKILLS**

- · Focused on problem
- Agile processes
- · Microservices architecture
- · Domain-Driven Design
- · Network protocols
- Database optimisation
- · Distributed systems
- Go
- PostgreSQL
- Redis
- Consul
- Kafka
- Docker
- Terraform

### **SOCIALS**

- @VitalyBolychev
- @ @vitalybolychev

## **LANGUAGES**

- English Intermediate
- Russian Native

#### REFERENCES

References are available on request

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Space307

January 2019 - Present

I had developed backend for e-wallet internet application using microservice architecture. Me and my team worked on payment processing as well as on general product features like a notification system. Now I'm working on trading platform which serves more than 15 000 clients online in peaks every day. I help to build system which carries on flexible trading conditions for each user depending on its trading experience.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

Devim

June 2016 - January 2019

I focused on development for financial projects. I helped the company to develop its own scalable, reliable microservice architecture. Participated in designing, implementing and releasing CRM system for country-wide financial company.

#### **Software Engineer**

MobileUp

February 2016 - June 2016

I participated in development of the city bike rental system on position of core backend developer. I communicated with hardware and mobile software teams. I facilitated development, testing, and releasing the project.

## **EDUCATION**

St. Petersburg State Electrotechnical University "LETI" Master's degree in Computer security